<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Landing Page on</title><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/</link><description>Recent content in Landing Page on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-AI-Apps-Pathway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-AI-Apps-Pathway/</guid><description>Pathway - AI-Driven Applications AI-Driven Applications Introduction [[AI For Devs - App Pathway - M5 Integrating AI in Applications|M5 Integrating AI in Applications]] Overview of popular LLM APIs (Groq) Setting up and authenticating with APIs LLM API calls and response handling Integrating AI services [[AI For Devs - App Pathway - M6 LLMs and Prompt Engineering|M6 LLMs and Prompt Engineering]] Introduction to prompt engineering Understanding and managing LLM API parameters (temperature, max tokens, etc.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-App-Pathway-M5-Integrating-AI-in-Applications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-App-Pathway-M5-Integrating-AI-in-Applications/</guid><description>M4 Integrating AI in Applications Azure Cognitive Services Example of Computer Vision with Azure Integrating AI Services into Applications If you&amp;rsquo;d like to use Azure services -&amp;gt; Azure for Students – Free Account Credit | Microsoft Azure</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-App-Pathway-M6-LLMs-and-Prompt-Engineering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-App-Pathway-M6-LLMs-and-Prompt-Engineering/</guid><description>M6 LLMs and Prompt Engineering LLM Settings Read / Watch: LLM Settings | Prompt Engineering Guide.
Understanding these settings will be important to getting the level of consistency and variability you want out of your LLMs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-App-Pathway-M8-Context-and-Knowledge-Management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-App-Pathway-M8-Context-and-Knowledge-Management/</guid><description>Context and Knowledge Management Read: What is a context window—and why does it matter? | Zapier Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) Using RAG and Vector Database Watch (and optionally follow along either locally or on Google Colab) with the following sections of Advanced Retrieval for AI with Chroma (deeplearning.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-Course-Project-Proposal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-Course-Project-Proposal/</guid><description>Project Proposal Assignment Introduction This proposal is your roadmap for a quarter-long project that will form a significant part of your learning experience and final grade.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-Course-Project-Rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-Course-Project-Rubric/</guid><description>Course Project Rubric Total Points: 100
Project Implementation (40 points) Completeness of project as outlined in proposal Technical complexity and depth Code Quality and Documentation (20 points) Well-organized, readable code with appropriate comments Comprehensive README file explaining project setup and execution Regular GitHub commits (at least once per week) showing consistent progress Analysis and Interpretation (15 points) Thorough analysis of results Clear interpretation and discussion of findings Final Presentation (25 points) Clear and engaging final presentation Visually appealing slides Demo (if included) is well executed, focused and supports the presentation *I do not want to see clicking through pages of an application with no clear plan or commentary.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-M1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-M1/</guid><description>M1 - AI Overview Learning Objectives These topics will be covered in this module&amp;rsquo;s knowledge check and entry ticket.
Understand the course structure, expectations, and requirements.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-M2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-M2/</guid><description>M2 - Applications of Machine Learning Learning Objectives These topics will be covered in this module&amp;rsquo;s knowledge check and entry ticket.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-M3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-M3/</guid><description>M3 - Working with Generative AI Learning Objectives These topics will be covered in this module&amp;rsquo;s knowledge check and entry ticket.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-M4-Assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-M4-Assignment/</guid><description>Assignment: Generative AI for Learning Overview In this assignment, you&amp;rsquo;ll explore how generative AI tools can assist in your learning process.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-M4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-M4/</guid><description>Using Generative AI Why LLMs Hallucinate Learning with Generative AI Coding with Generative AI Using Copilot Get Copilot for free -&amp;gt; Students - GitHub Education Learning Paths and Final Project Work About half of the time spent on this class each week should be put towards your chosen pathway and final project.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-M5-Assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-M5-Assignment/</guid><description>Practice Assignment - Machine Learning with Decision Trees and Random Forests Kaggle Lessons: Learn Intro to Machine Learning | Kaggle</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-M5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-M5/</guid><description>Traditional Machine Learning and Model Evaluation Learning Objectives These topics will be covered in this module&amp;rsquo;s knowledge check and entry ticket.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-M8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-M8/</guid><description>Neural Networks and Deep Learning Learning Objectives These topics will be covered in this module&amp;rsquo;s knowledge check and entry ticket.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-ML-Pathway-M5-Exploratory-Data-Analysis-EDA/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-ML-Pathway-M5-Exploratory-Data-Analysis-EDA/</guid><description>M4 Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) Read: The Machine Learning Life Cycle Explained | DataCamp Basics Stats for ML Exploratory Data Analysis with Python Optional (but highly recommended): If you&amp;rsquo;re serious about getting into data analytics and/or machine learning, these are very important concepts!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-ML-Pathway-M6-Data-Preparation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-ML-Pathway-M6-Data-Preparation/</guid><description>M6 Data Preparation Data cleaning techniques Handling missing data (imputation strategies) Dealing with categorical data (one-hot encoding) Feature scaling and normalization Handling class imbalance Missing Data and Imputation Handling Categorical Data Feature Scaling *If you did not watch the standard deviation and normal distribution videos from last week you&amp;rsquo;ll want to start with those to understand the standardizations discussed in this video [[AI For Devs - ML Pathway - M5 Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA)#Optional (but highly recommended)]].</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-ML-Pathway-M8-Machine-Learning-Algorithms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-ML-Pathway-M8-Machine-Learning-Algorithms/</guid><description>Machine Learning Algorithms Classification Models Confusion Matrix Classification Metrics Review: Example ML Model Implementations Code examples of how you might implement each of these models for different tasks.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-ML-Pathway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-ML-Pathway/</guid><description>Pathway - Supervised ML and Analytics ML Analytics Pathway Introduction [[AI For Devs - ML Pathway - M5 Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA)|M5 Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA)]] ML workflow Basic statistical measures (mean, median, mode) Data distribution analysis (histograms, box plots) Correlation analysis (scatter plots, correlation matrices) Identifying outliers and anomalies Using libraries like Pandas, Matplotlib, and Seaborn for EDA Creating insightful visualizations (bar charts, heatmaps, pair plots) Drawing initial insights from the data [[AI For Devs - ML Pathway - M6 Data Preparation|Module 6 - Data Preparation]] Data cleaning techniques Handling missing data (imputation strategies) Dealing with categorical data (one-hot encoding) Feature scaling and normalization Handling outliers (when to remove, when to keep) Handling class imbalance [[AI For Devs - ML Pathway - M8 Machine Learning Algorithms|Module 8 - Machine Learning Algorithms]] Train / Test / Val Linear / Logistic Regression Decision Trees Random Forests / Boosting vs Bagging Understanding Accuracy and the Confusion Matrix Module 9 - Model Training and Evaluation Cross-validation Overfitting and handling it Learning and validation curves Module 10 - Model Improvements Ensemble methods Voting classifiers Stacking Blending Hyperparameter tuning Grid search Random search Bayesian optimization Error analysis and iterative improvement Module 11 - Model Deployment Creating a simple API for model deployment (using Flask) Monitoring model performance in production Ethical considerations in AI/ML Bias and fairness in machine learning Privacy concerns and data protection Transparency and explainability of models Responsible AI practices Legal and regulatory considerations (e.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-_-Lessons-Index/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-_-Lessons-Index/</guid><description>Introduction to AI and Machine Learning Core Content [[AI For Devs - M1]] [[AI For Devs - M2]] [[AI For Devs MISC - AI In-Class EDA]] [[AI For Devs - M3]] [[AI For Devs - Course Project Proposal]] [[AI For Devs - M4]] [[AI For Devs - M4 Assignment]] [[AI For Devs MISC - AI In-Class Copilot]] [[AI For Devs - M5]] [[AI For Devs - M5 Assignment]] AI For Devs - M6 No class AI For Devs - M7 [[AI For Devs MISC - AI In-Class Life Expectancy Scenario]] [[AI For Devs - M8]] AI For Devs - M9 Intro AI For Devs - M10 Intro Pathways and Final Project [[AI For Devs - Course Project Rubric]] [[AI For Devs - ML Pathway]] [[AI For Devs - AI Apps Pathway]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-MISC-AI-In-Class-Copilot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-MISC-AI-In-Class-Copilot/</guid><description>Serving ML Models Learning Objectives Get comfortable using resources and AI tools to quickly jump into new technologies See how the machine learning models you develop can be used in applications Goal Convert your existing linear regression model into an API-accessible service using Flask.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-MISC-AI-In-Class-EDA/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-MISC-AI-In-Class-EDA/</guid><description>EDA and Notebook Practice Introduction AI is fundamentally about data. Why?
Because at its core, that&amp;rsquo;s what AI systems learn from and operate on.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-MISC-AI-In-Class-Life-Expectancy-Scenario/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/AI-For-Devs-MISC-AI-In-Class-Life-Expectancy-Scenario/</guid><description>Life Expectancy Scenario Task Overview Imagine that you are a data scientist at a global health organization. The organization wants to understand the key factors affecting life expectancy across different countries and to develop a model that can predict life expectancy based on these factors.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-Final-Project-Assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-Final-Project-Assignment/</guid><description>Final Project Assignment For your final project in this course, you have the opportunity to dive into an AI topic that interests you.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W1-A-Brief-History-of-AI/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W1-A-Brief-History-of-AI/</guid><description>A Brief History of AI Cool Things to Explore (Optional) Great documentary on AlphaGo AI - AlphaGo - The Movie | Full award-winning documentary (youtube.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W1-AI-Tasks-and-Types-of-Machine-Learning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W1-AI-Tasks-and-Types-of-Machine-Learning/</guid><description>AI Tasks and Types of Machine Learning Lessons [[AI - W1 Introduction]] [[AI - W1 A Brief History of AI]] AI - W1 AI Tasks and Types of Learning</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W1-Introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W1-Introduction/</guid><description>Week 1 Introduction Learning Objectives These topics are what will be covered in this week&amp;rsquo;s knowledge check and entry ticket quiz.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W10-Fine-tuning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W10-Fine-tuning/</guid><description>Fine-tuning LLMs Watch the following sections of Finetuning Large Language Models (deeplearning.ai):
Introduction Why finetune Where finetuning fits in Instruction finetuning (Optional) Data Preparation (Optional) Evaluation and iterations You may follow along but it is not required for this section.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W10-Introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W10-Introduction/</guid><description>Learning Objectives Understand and demonstrate the use of memory in AI models. Explore the basics and applications of Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W10-Memory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W10-Memory/</guid><description>Memory If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already, make sure to watch the LangChain for LLM Application Development (deeplearning.ai) lesson on memory. This will be part of our in-class activity.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W10-RAG/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W10-RAG/</guid><description>Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) Watch and follow along (either locally or on Google Colab) with the following sections of Advanced Retrieval for AI with Chroma (deeplearning.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W2-Assignment-Multiple-Linear-Regression/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W2-Assignment-Multiple-Linear-Regression/</guid><description>Assignment - Multiple Linear Regression Instructions Find a dataset suitable for multiple linear regression analysis. Find Open Datasets and Machine Learning Projects | Kaggle Select the columns (features) you want to use as predictor variables and the column you want to predict (target variable).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W2-Introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W2-Introduction/</guid><description>Week 2 Learning Objectives These topics are what will be covered in this week&amp;rsquo;s knowledge check and entry ticket quiz.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W2-Jupyter-Notebooks-and-Google-Colab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W2-Jupyter-Notebooks-and-Google-Colab/</guid><description>Jupyter Notebooks and Google Colab Lessons [[AI - W2 Introduction]] AI - W2 Jupyter Notebooks and Google Colab Next: [[AI - W2 Python Refresher and Pandas]] [[AI - W2 Statistical Modeling and Implementing Linear Regression]] [[AI - W2 Assignment - Multiple Linear Regression]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W2-Python-Refresher-and-Pandas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W2-Python-Refresher-and-Pandas/</guid><description>Python Refresher and Pandas Lessons [[AI - W2 Introduction]] [[AI - W2 Jupyter Notebooks and Google Colab]] AI - W2 Python Refresher and Pandas Next: [[AI - W2 Statistical Modeling and Implementing Linear Regression]] [[AI - W2 Assignment - Multiple Linear Regression]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W2-Statistical-Modeling-and-Implementing-Linear-Regression/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W2-Statistical-Modeling-and-Implementing-Linear-Regression/</guid><description>Statistical Modeling and Implementing Linear Regression Links Study Hours Dataset: Student Study Hours (kaggle.com) Admissions Dataset: Data for Admission in the University (kaggle.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W3-Assignment-Decision-Trees-Random-Forests-and-Model-Validation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W3-Assignment-Decision-Trees-Random-Forests-and-Model-Validation/</guid><description>Assignment - Decision Trees, Random Forests and Model Validation Kaggle Lessons: Learn Intro to Machine Learning | Kaggle
I highly recommend watching both of these videos to help give a more visual and intuitive understanding of how decision trees and random forests function:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W3-Introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W3-Introduction/</guid><description>Week 3 Learning Objectives These topics are what will be covered in this week&amp;rsquo;s knowledge check and entry ticket quiz.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W3-Model-Validation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W3-Model-Validation/</guid><description>Model Validation Lessons [[AI - W3 Introduction]] AI - W3 Model Validation Next: [[AI - W3 Assignment - Decision Trees, Random Forests and Model Validation]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W4-Assignment-Introduction-to-Deep-Learning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W4-Assignment-Introduction-to-Deep-Learning/</guid><description>Assignment - Introduction to Deep Learning Complete all section of the Learn Intro to Deep Learning course on Kaggle (est. 3-4 hours).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W4-How-Neural-Networks-Learn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W4-How-Neural-Networks-Learn/</guid><description>How Neural Networks Learn Optional Resources Gradient descent, how neural networks learn | Chapter 2, Deep learning (youtube.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W4-Introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W4-Introduction/</guid><description>Week 4 Learning Objectives These topics are what will be covered in this week&amp;rsquo;s knowledge check and entry ticket quiz.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W4-Neural-Network-and-Deep-Learning-Overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W4-Neural-Network-and-Deep-Learning-Overview/</guid><description>Neural Network and Deep Learning Overview Optional Resources Neural networks: representation. (jeremyjordan.me) But what is a neural network?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W4-TensorFlow-Playground/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W4-TensorFlow-Playground/</guid><description>TensorFlow Playground Link -&amp;gt; TensorFlow Playground Lessons [[AI - W4 Introduction]] [[AI - W4 Neural Network and Deep Learning Overview]] [[AI - W4 How Neural Networks Learn]] AI - W4 TensorFlow Playground Next: [[AI - W4 Assignment - Introduction to Deep Learning]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W5-Assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W5-Assignment/</guid><description>Assignment - Computer Vision Complete all section of the Learn Computer Vision course on Kaggle (est. 3-4 hours). Submit your completed file for the final exercise (Data Augmentation) to the assignment in canvas.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W5-Introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W5-Introduction/</guid><description>Week 5 Learning Objectives These topics are what will be covered in this week&amp;rsquo;s knowledge check and entry ticket quiz.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W5-Types-of-Neural-Network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W5-Types-of-Neural-Network/</guid><description>Types of Neural Network Optional Resources 2D Visualization of a Convolutional Neural Network (adamharley.com) Lessons [[AI - W5 Introduction]] AI - W5 Types of Neural Networks Next: [[AI - W5 Assignment]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W6-Applications-and-Challenges-of-RL/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W6-Applications-and-Challenges-of-RL/</guid><description>Applications and Challenges of RL Lessons [[AI - W6 Introduction]] [[AI - W6 Basics of RL]] [[AI - W6 Types of RL]] AI - W6 Applications and Challenges of RL Next: [[AI - W6 Assignment]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W6-Assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W6-Assignment/</guid><description>W6 Assignment Visual Studio Code: Visual Studio Code - Code Editing. Redefined Python: Python Release Python 3.11.9 | Python.org</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W6-Basics-of-RL/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W6-Basics-of-RL/</guid><description>Basics of RL Lessons [[AI - W6 Introduction]] AI - W6 Basics of RL Next: [[AI - W6 Types of RL]] [[AI - W6 Applications and Challenges of RL]] [[AI - W6 Assignment]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W6-Introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W6-Introduction/</guid><description>Week 6 Learning Objectives These topics are what will be covered in this week&amp;rsquo;s knowledge check and entry ticket quiz.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W6-Types-of-RL/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W6-Types-of-RL/</guid><description>Types of RL Supplemental Resources Simple overview of RL terminology and concepts: Reinforcement Learning: Crash Course AI #9 - YouTube Lessons [[AI - W6 Introduction]] [[AI - W6 Basics of RL]] AI - W6 Types of RL Next: [[AI - W6 Applications and Challenges of RL]] [[AI - W6 Assignment]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W7-Assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W7-Assignment/</guid><description>W7 Assignment Instructions:
Choose a topic or skill you&amp;rsquo;d like to learn about that you&amp;rsquo;re not very familiar with. It should be conceptual, not just factual.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W7-Basics-of-Working-with-Generative-AI-and-LLMs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W7-Basics-of-Working-with-Generative-AI-and-LLMs/</guid><description>Basics of Working with Generative AI and LLMs Chat Web UIs https://chatgpt.com/ https://gemini.google.com/ https://claude.ai/chat/ Platforms / APIs https://platform.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W7-Discussion-Post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W7-Discussion-Post/</guid><description>Lessons [[AI - W7 Introduction]] [[AI - W7 Basics of Working with Generative AI and LLMs]] [[AI - W7 Prompt Engineering]] Next: [[AI - W7 Learning with Generative AI]] [[AI - W7 Assignment]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W7-Introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W7-Introduction/</guid><description>Week 7 Learning Objectives These topics are what will be covered in this week&amp;rsquo;s knowledge check and entry ticket quiz.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W7-Learning-with-Generative-AI/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W7-Learning-with-Generative-AI/</guid><description>Learning with Generative AI NOTE: Content from this video will not appear on the week 7 entry ticket or be required in order to complete the week 7 discussion post!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W7-Prompt-Engineering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W7-Prompt-Engineering/</guid><description>Prompt Engineering Watch all sections of ChatGPT Prompt Engineering for Developers - deeplearning.ai (about 1.5 hours) Lessons [[AI - W7 Introduction]] [[AI - W7 Basics of Working with Generative AI and LLMs]] AI - W7 Prompt Engineering Next: [[AI - W7 Learning with Generative AI]] [[AI - W7 Assignment]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W8-Assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W8-Assignment/</guid><description>W8 / W9 Assignment - Final Project Proposals Review the Final Project Assignment [[AI - Final Project Assignment]]
Create Your Final Project Proposal To ensure that your final project is on the right track and aligns with the course requirements, you will submit a project proposal.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W8-Calling-LLM-APIs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W8-Calling-LLM-APIs/</guid><description>Calling LLM APIs Lessons [[AI - W8 Introduction]] AI - W8 Calling LLM APIs Next: [[AI - W8 LangChain Prompts]] [[AI - W8 LangChain LLM Chains]] [[AI - W8 LangChain Agents and Tools]] [[AI - W8 LangChain for LLM Application Development Lessons]] [[AI - W8 Assignment]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W8-Introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W8-Introduction/</guid><description>Learning Objectives These topics are what will be covered in knowledge checks and entry ticket quizzes.
Understand how to use language models (LLMs) in applications by calling an API endpoint.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W8-LangChain-Agents-and-Tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W8-LangChain-Agents-and-Tools/</guid><description>LangChain Agents and Tools Lessons [[AI - W8 Introduction]] [[AI - W8 Calling LLM APIs]] [[AI - W8 LangChain Prompts]] [[AI - W8 LangChain LLM Chains]] AI - W8 LangChain Agents and Tools Next: [[AI - W8 LangChain for LLM Application Development Lessons]] [[AI - W8 Assignment]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W8-LangChain-for-LLM-Application-Development-Lessons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W8-LangChain-for-LLM-Application-Development-Lessons/</guid><description>LangChain Lessons Watch and follow along (either locally or on Google Colab) with the following sections of LangChain for LLM Application Development (deeplearning.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W8-LangChain-LLM-Chains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W8-LangChain-LLM-Chains/</guid><description>LangChain LLM Chains Lessons [[AI - W8 Introduction]] [[AI - W8 Calling LLM APIs]] [[AI - W8 LangChain Prompts]] AI - W8 LangChain LLM Chains Next: [[AI - W8 LangChain Agents and Tools]] [[AI - W8 LangChain for LLM Application Development Lessons]] [[AI - W8 Assignment]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W8-LangChain-Prompts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-W8-LangChain-Prompts/</guid><description>LangChain Prompts Lessons [[AI - W8 Introduction]] [[AI - W8 Calling LLM APIs]] AI - W8 LangChain Prompts Next: [[AI - W8 LangChain LLM Chains]] [[AI - W8 LangChain Agents and Tools]] [[AI - W8 LangChain for LLM Application Development Lessons]] [[AI - W8 Assignment]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-_-Lesson-Index/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/AI-Spring24/AI-_-Lesson-Index/</guid><description>Introduction to AI and Machine Learning [[AI - W1 Introduction]] [[AI - W2 Introduction]] [[AI - W3 Introduction]] [[AI - W4 Introduction]] [[AI - W5 Introduction]] [[AI - W6 Introduction]] [[AI - W7 Introduction]] [[AI - W8 Introduction]] [[AI - W10 Introduction]] [[AI - Final Project Assignment]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/NET-Example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/Archive/NET-Example/</guid><description>Model
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 public class Book { public int Id { get; set; } public string Title { get; set; } public string Author { get; set; } public int Year { get; set; } } Service</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/LEGACY-SQL-_-Lesson-Index/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/LEGACY-SQL-_-Lesson-Index/</guid><description>SQL For Data Analytics Lesson Index Module One:
Introduction to Databases and Relational Tables [[SQL - W2 Select and Filter Data - Introduction]] [[SQL - W3 Table JOINs - Introduction]] [[SQL - W4 Querying and Analysis for HR Database Assignment Introduction]] Module Two:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/MISC-305-Midterm-Practice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/MISC-305-Midterm-Practice/</guid><description>Midterm: JavaScript Technical Interview Practice These questions are designed to help prepare you for the [[MISC - 305 Midterm|305 Midterm]]. Once you feel familiar with the JavaScript topics, try taking these without using notes for practice.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/MISC-305-Midterm-Redo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/MISC-305-Midterm-Redo/</guid><description>Midterm: JavaScript Technical Interview Redo Overview If you are not satisfied with your performance on the midterm technical interview you have the opportunity take it again.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/MISC-305-Midterm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/MISC-305-Midterm/</guid><description>Midterm: JavaScript Technical Interview Overview This midterm will consist of a 15-minute one-on-one session with your instructor via Zoom. You will be asked to share your screen of Visual Studio Code to write code and answer technical questions.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/MISC-Node-Demo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/MISC-Node-Demo/</guid><description>pizza-node-demo/views at starter · kellerflint/pizza-node-demo (github.com)
1 2 // Parse URL-encoded bodies (as sent by HTML forms) app.use(express.urlencoded({ extended: true })); 1 2 // Passing order details to the view res.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/MISC-Node-Lessons-OLD/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/MISC-Node-Lessons-OLD/</guid><description>Node Lessons Installing Node Downloads:
Node.js (nodejs.org) Visual Studio Code - Code Editing. Redefined Project Setup and Hello World App Terminal Commands from Video Create the project:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/MISC-Node-Project-Setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/MISC-Node-Project-Setup/</guid><description>Node Project Setup Installing Node Downloads:
Node.js (nodejs.org) Visual Studio Code - Code Editing. Redefined You can test that node installed successfully by opening your terminal and typing node -v.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Final-Exam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Final-Exam/</guid><description>Final Exam Info There is a required in-person final exam for this course on Monday June 17th from 12:00-2:00pm PST at the Auburn Center in room AC 310 (1221 D St NE, Auburn, WA 98002).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Practice-Final/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Practice-Final/</guid><description>The format and topics covered in this practice final closely mirror what you will encounter on the final exam. To ensure you&amp;rsquo;re fully prepared, these practice questions are designed to be slightly more challenging versions of the types of questions you&amp;rsquo;ll be asked in the final exam.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W10-Advanced-Querying-Aggregate-Functions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W10-Advanced-Querying-Aggregate-Functions/</guid><description>Advanced Querying - Aggregate Functions Practice Questions Use the magic store database for the following queries.
Write a query to find the total number of orders placed in 2021.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W10-Advanced-Querying-Calculating-Values/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W10-Advanced-Querying-Calculating-Values/</guid><description>Advanced Querying Topics Part 1 - Calculating Values Practice Questions Use the magic store database for the following queries.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W10-Advanced-Querying-Column-Aliasing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W10-Advanced-Querying-Column-Aliasing/</guid><description>Advanced Querying - Column Aliasing Practice Questions Use the magic store database for the following queries.
Write a query to show all products that cost more than 1 and less than 100.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W10-Advanced-Querying-Data-Analytics-with-GROUP-BY/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W10-Advanced-Querying-Data-Analytics-with-GROUP-BY/</guid><description>Grouping and Data Analytics - Data Analytics with GROUP BY Lessons [[SQL - W10 Advanced Querying - Introduction]] [[SQL - W10 Advanced Querying - Aggregate Functions]] [[SQL - W10 Advanced Querying - Column Aliasing]] [[SQL - W10 Advanced Querying - Calculating Values]] [[SQL - W10 Advanced Querying - Northwind Database]] [[SQL - W10 Advanced Querying - GROUP BY]] SQL - W10 Advanced Querying - Data Analytics with GROUP BY Next: [[SQL - W10 Advanced Querying and Data Analytics Assignment]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W10-Advanced-Querying-GROUP-BY/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W10-Advanced-Querying-GROUP-BY/</guid><description>Grouping and Data Analytics - GROUP BY Lessons [[SQL - W10 Advanced Querying - Introduction]] [[SQL - W10 Advanced Querying - Aggregate Functions]] [[SQL - W10 Advanced Querying - Column Aliasing]] [[SQL - W10 Advanced Querying - Calculating Values]] [[SQL - W10 Advanced Querying - Northwind Database]] SQL - W10 Advanced Querying - GROUP BY Next: [[SQL - W10 Advanced Querying - Data Analytics with GROUP BY]] [[SQL - W10 Advanced Querying and Data Analytics Assignment]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W10-Advanced-Querying-Introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W10-Advanced-Querying-Introduction/</guid><description>Advanced Querying - Introduction Initialize the Magic Store Database DROP the tables from your previous assignment(s), if necessary Run the following script to populate your database -&amp;gt; MagicStoreScript (github.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W10-Advanced-Querying-Northwind-Database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W10-Advanced-Querying-Northwind-Database/</guid><description>Northwind Database Initialize the Northwind Database DROP the tables from your previous assignment(s), if necessary Run the following script to populate your database -&amp;gt; NorthwindScript (github.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W10-Advanced-Querying-and-Data-Analytics-Assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W10-Advanced-Querying-and-Data-Analytics-Assignment/</guid><description>Advanced Querying and Data Analytics Assignment Use the Magic Store database for the following queries. Each query is worth 5 points.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-Creating-a-Database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-Creating-a-Database/</guid><description>Select and Filter Data - Creating a Database Before getting started you&amp;rsquo;ll want to make sure that you have a text or code editor installed.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-Introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-Introduction/</guid><description>Select and Filter Data - Introduction In this section, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover key SQL concepts to help you retrieve, filter and sort the information in your databases.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-Logical-Operators/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-Logical-Operators/</guid><description>Select and Filter Data - Logical Operators Logical operators are essential in SQL for combining multiple conditions in the WHERE clause and adding flexibility to your queries.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-Note-on-Semicolons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-Note-on-Semicolons/</guid><description>Select and Filter Data - Note on Semicolons Why use semicolons? So far we&amp;rsquo;ve only been executing a single query at a time but we could run more.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-ORDER-BY/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-ORDER-BY/</guid><description>Select and Filter Data - ORDER BY The ORDER BY clause is used to sort the result set of a query by one or more columns.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-Practice-Assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-Practice-Assignment/</guid><description>Select and Filter Data - Practice Assignment Practice Questions In addition to the practice problems from the lesson pages, write queries to do the following:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-Running-Scripts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-Running-Scripts/</guid><description>Select and Filter Data - Running Scripts To get started with hands-on practice, you&amp;rsquo;ll need data to populate your database.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-SELECT-Statement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-SELECT-Statement/</guid><description>Select and Filter Data - SELECT Statement Database Basics Refresher Databases exist to help us store and manage large amounts of information in an organized way.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-SQL-Comments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-SQL-Comments/</guid><description>Select and Filter Data - SQL Comments Comments in SQL are used to explain sections of SQL statements, or to prevent execution of SQL statements.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-WHERE-Clause-and-Comparison-Operators/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W2-Select-and-Filter-Data-WHERE-Clause-and-Comparison-Operators/</guid><description>Select and Filter Data - WHERE Clause and Comparison Operators The WHERE clause in SQL is used to filter records from a table, returning only those that meet a specific condition.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W3-Magic-Store-Database-Overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W3-Magic-Store-Database-Overview/</guid><description>Magic Store Database Overview Initialize the Magic Store Database DROP the tables from your previous assignment(s), if necessary Run the following script to populate your database -&amp;gt; MagicStoreScript (github.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W3-One-to-Many-JOINs-Practice-Assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W3-One-to-Many-JOINs-Practice-Assignment/</guid><description>One-to-Many JOINs - Practice Assignment Write a query to list all orders and the clients who placed them, sorted by the order date.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W3-Table-JOINs-DROP-Tables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W3-Table-JOINs-DROP-Tables/</guid><description>DROP Tables DROP Tables The DROP command in SQL is used to remove objects from the database. It&amp;rsquo;s a powerful command that can permanently delete tables, databases, views, or indexes.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W3-Table-JOINs-Filter-and-Sort-with-JOINs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W3-Table-JOINs-Filter-and-Sort-with-JOINs/</guid><description>Filter and Sort with JOINs Using WHERE and ORDER BY with JOINs We can still utilize the clauses from previous lessons to filter and sort on joined data.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W3-Table-JOINs-Introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W3-Table-JOINs-Introduction/</guid><description>Table JOINs - Introduction In this section, we will:
Interact with databases that have multiple related tables. Discuss the different types of relationships tables can have with each other and how these relationships shape the way we retrieve and interpret data.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W3-Table-JOINs-JOIN-Tables-with-One-to-Many-Relationships/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W3-Table-JOINs-JOIN-Tables-with-One-to-Many-Relationships/</guid><description>JOIN Tables with One-to-Many Relationships Understanding JOINs in One-to-Many Relationships Given our bookstore database example from the previous lesson:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W3-Table-JOINs-One-to-Many-Relationships/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W3-Table-JOINs-One-to-Many-Relationships/</guid><description>Introduction to One-to-Many Relationships What is a One-to-Many Relationship? In relational databases, a one-to-many relationship is the most fundamental type of relationship.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W4-HR-Database-Overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W4-HR-Database-Overview/</guid><description>HR Database Overview Initialize the HR Database DROP the tables from your previous assignment(s), if necessary See [[SQL - W3 Table JOINs - DROP Tables]] for a refresher on dropping tables.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W4-JOINing-Multiple-Tables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W4-JOINing-Multiple-Tables/</guid><description>JOINing Multiple Tables Lessons [[SQL - W4 Querying and Analysis for HR Database Assignment Introduction]] SQL - W4 JOINing Multiple Tables Next: [[SQL - W7 Table Aliasing]] [[SQL - W4 HR Database Overview]] [[SQL - W4 Querying and Analysis for HR Database Assignment]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W4-Querying-and-Analysis-for-HR-Database-Assignment-Introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W4-Querying-and-Analysis-for-HR-Database-Assignment-Introduction/</guid><description>Querying and Analysis for HR Database Assignment Introduction This assignment is divided into three sections, each aimed at developing a different aspect of your querying and analytical skills.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W4-Querying-and-Analysis-for-HR-Database-Assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W4-Querying-and-Analysis-for-HR-Database-Assignment/</guid><description>Querying and Analysis for HR Database Assignment Every questions should be answered with exactly one query. You will need exactly one SELECT statement per question.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W5-Data-Types-and-Nullability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W5-Data-Types-and-Nullability/</guid><description>Data Types and Nullability In addition to showing basic structure of tables and their relationships, Entity Relationship Diagrams (ERDs) can also give us more insight into the columns.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W5-Entity-Relationship-Diagram-Structure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W5-Entity-Relationship-Diagram-Structure/</guid><description>Entity Relationship Diagram Structure Entity Relationship Diagrams come in various formats, but they share common elements that help us understand the architecture of a database.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W5-Entity-Relationship-Diagrams-Practice-Assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W5-Entity-Relationship-Diagrams-Practice-Assignment/</guid><description>Entity Relationship Diagrams Practice Assignment In addition to the practice problems from the lesson pages, write queries to do the following:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W5-Introduction-to-Entity-Relationship-Diagrams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W5-Introduction-to-Entity-Relationship-Diagrams/</guid><description>Introduction to Entity Relationship Diagrams Entity Relationship Diagrams (ERDs) are a fundamental part of database design and architecture. They provide a visual representation of the data and how entities within a database relate to each other.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W5-Querying-from-ERDs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W5-Querying-from-ERDs/</guid><description>Querying from ERDs Practice questions College Courses Diagram Write a SQL query to retrieve the start date of all classes taught by the instructor with the first_name &amp;ldquo;Tina&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W5-Representing-Relationships/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W5-Representing-Relationships/</guid><description>Representing Relationships Entity Relationship Diagrams (ERDs) not only show us the entities and their attributes but also how these entities interact with each other.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W7-JOIN-Tables-with-Many-to-Many-Relationships/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W7-JOIN-Tables-with-Many-to-Many-Relationships/</guid><description>JOIN Tables with Many-to-Many Relationships Understanding JOINs in Many-to-Many Relationships Given our bookstore database example from the previous lesson:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W7-Many-to-Many-Relationships/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W7-Many-to-Many-Relationships/</guid><description>Many-to-Many Relationships Introduction to Many-to-Many Relationships A many-to-many relationship in databases occurs when multiple records in one table are associated with multiple records in another table.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W7-Practice-Assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W7-Practice-Assignment/</guid><description>Use the Magic Store Database ([[SQL - W3 Magic Store Database Overview]]) to complete the practice questions for week.
In addition to the practice problems from the lesson pages, write queries to do the following:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W7-Table-Aliasing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W7-Table-Aliasing/</guid><description>Table Aliasing What is Table Aliasing? Table aliasing involves giving a table in your SQL query a temporary name. This temporary name (aka alias) is often an abbreviation of the full table name.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W8-Creating-Entity-Relationship-Diagrams-CREATE-Many-to-Many-Tables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W8-Creating-Entity-Relationship-Diagrams-CREATE-Many-to-Many-Tables/</guid><description>Practice Questions (3pts) Write the CREATE statements for the pets, owners and pets_owners tables in the diagram below. Lessons [[SQL Analytics M8 - Entity Relationship Diagrams]] [[SQL - W8 Creating Entity Relationship Diagrams - CREATE One to Many Tables]] Creating Entity Relationship Diagrams - CREATE Many to Many Tables Next: [[SQL Analytics M7 - Composite Primary Keys]] [[SQL Analytics M7 - Creating Entity Relationship Diagrams]] [[SQL - W8 Creating Entity Relationship Diagrams - Practice Assignment]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W8-Creating-Entity-Relationship-Diagrams-CREATE-One-to-Many-Tables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W8-Creating-Entity-Relationship-Diagrams-CREATE-One-to-Many-Tables/</guid><description>Practice Questions (2pts) Write the CREATE statements for the users and posts tables in the diagram below. Lessons [[SQL Analytics M8 - Entity Relationship Diagrams]] Creating Entity Relationship Diagrams - CREATE One to Many Tables Next: [[SQL - W8 Creating Entity Relationship Diagrams - CREATE Many to Many Tables]] [[SQL Analytics M7 - Composite Primary Keys]] [[SQL Analytics M7 - Creating Entity Relationship Diagrams]] [[SQL - W8 Creating Entity Relationship Diagrams - Practice Assignment]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W8-Creating-Entity-Relationship-Diagrams-Practice-Assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-W8-Creating-Entity-Relationship-Diagrams-Practice-Assignment/</guid><description>Creating Entity Relationship Diagrams - Practice Assignment Lessons [[SQL Analytics M8 - Entity Relationship Diagrams]] [[SQL - W8 Creating Entity Relationship Diagrams - CREATE One to Many Tables]] [[SQL - W8 Creating Entity Relationship Diagrams - CREATE Many to Many Tables]] [[SQL Analytics M7 - Composite Primary Keys]] [[SQL Analytics M7 - Creating Entity Relationship Diagrams]] Creating Entity Relationship Diagrams - Practice Assignment</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-ZCUT-Creating-Tables-in-ERDs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-ZCUT-Creating-Tables-in-ERDs/</guid><description>Creating Tables in ERDs Practice questions College Courses Diagram Write CREATE statements for the student and instructor tables. INSERT two rows of data into each table.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-ZCUT-W10-Advanced-Querying-Topics-JOIN-Refresher/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-ZCUT-W10-Advanced-Querying-Topics-JOIN-Refresher/</guid><description>Advanced Querying Topics Part 1 - JOIN Refresher Need a refresher on JOINs? See our lessons on [[SQL - W3 Table JOINs - One-to-Many Relationships]].</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-Midterm-Practice-Questions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-Midterm-Practice-Questions/</guid><description>Midterm Practice Questions The midterm questions will be similar to these. Take some time to work through these without notes. A link to the solutions is at the bottom of the page.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-Midterm-Practice-Solutions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-Midterm-Practice-Solutions/</guid><description>Midterm Practice Solutions [[SQL Analytics - Midterm Practice Questions|Back: Midterm Practice Questions]] Without Grouping / Aggregation 1 2 3 /* #1 Display all products with a price between $10 and $20.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-Northwind-Database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-Northwind-Database/</guid><description>Northwind Database Initialize the Northwind Database Create a new database/schema for the Northwind database Run the following script to populate your database -&amp;gt; NorthwindScript (github.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-Supplemental-Materials-Example-Opportunity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-Supplemental-Materials-Example-Opportunity/</guid><description>Client: Walgreens, United States, 200 Wilmot Road Deerfield
Opportunity Name: Appointment Tracking App for Walgreens
Estimated Revenue: 5 million
Created On: 22-10-19</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-Supplemental-Materials-Opportunity-Steps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-Supplemental-Materials-Opportunity-Steps/</guid><description>Steps in an opportunity: Step 1 - Confirm Opportunity: Follow up with the client to confirm the opportunity Step 2 - Create Cost Estimation: Estimate the cost of completing the project and identify profit margins Step 3 - Create Statement of Work: Create Statement of Work document that outlines everything that will need to go into the project Step 4 - Review Statement of Work: Review statement of work with management Step 5 - Get Signatures: Get sign off from client</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-Supplemental-Materials-Sales-Team-Members/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-Supplemental-Materials-Sales-Team-Members/</guid><description>Current sales team members: Name: Annabeth Chase, Role: Sales Representative Name: David Martinez, Role: Sales Representative Name: Si Wang-mu, Role: Manager Name: Duncan Idaho, Role: Sales Representative</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-_-Lesson-Index/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-_-Lesson-Index/</guid><description>SQL For Data Analytics Lesson Index [[SQL Analytics M1 - Introduction to Data Analytics and Relational Data]] [[SQL Analytics M2 - Basic Querying]] [[SQL Analytics M3 - Grouping and Aggregation]] [[SQL Analytics M4 - SQL for Data Analytics]] [[SQL Analytics - Midterm Practice Questions]] [[SQL Analytics M5 - Table JOINs]] [[SQL Analytics M6 - Entity Relationship Diagrams and Table Creation]] [[SQL Analytics M7 - Many-to-Many Relationships and Entity Relationship Diagrams]] [[SQL Analytics M8 - Database Design]] [[SQL Analytics M9 - Database Design Peer Review Assignment]] [[SQL Analytics Final - Practice Questions]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-Final-Practice-Questions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-Final-Practice-Questions/</guid><description>SQL Analytics Final - Practice Questions Write a query to show the order ID, order date of orders and the first and last name of the employee who handled the order.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-Final-Practice-Solutions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-Final-Practice-Solutions/</guid><description>See Questions: [[SQL Analytics Final - Practice Questions]] Final Practice Solutions Write a query to show the order ID, order date of orders and the first and last name of the employee who handled the order.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M1-Basics-of-Data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M1-Basics-of-Data/</guid><description>Basics of Data Back: [[SQL Analytics M1 - Introduction to Data Analytics and Relational Data]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M1-Databases-and-Relational-Data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M1-Databases-and-Relational-Data/</guid><description>Databases and Relational Data Back: [[SQL Analytics M1 - Introduction to Data Analytics and Relational Data]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M1-Introduction-to-Data-Analytics-and-Relational-Data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M1-Introduction-to-Data-Analytics-and-Relational-Data/</guid><description>Lessons and Practice - Introduction to Data Analytics and Relational Data [[SQL Analytics M1 - Learning to Learn|Learning to Learn]] (25 min) Explain the concept of &amp;ldquo;distributed practice&amp;rdquo; in your own words and why it&amp;rsquo;s more effective than cramming.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M1-Learning-to-Learn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M1-Learning-to-Learn/</guid><description>Learning to Learn Back: [[SQL Analytics M1 - Introduction to Data Analytics and Relational Data]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M1-SQL-for-Data-Analytics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M1-SQL-for-Data-Analytics/</guid><description>SQL for Data Analytics Back: [[SQL Analytics M1 - Introduction to Data Analytics and Relational Data]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M2-Basic-Querying/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M2-Basic-Querying/</guid><description>Lessons and Practice - Basic Querying [[SQL Analytics M2 - Installing MySQL Workbench and MariaDB|Installing MySQL Workbench and MariaDB]] (17 min) After successfully setting up MySQL Workbench and MariaDB, take a screenshot of your working editor with your name in an open file (see canvas assignment for example) and submit it to the &amp;ldquo;M2 Practice - Editor Screenshot&amp;rdquo; assignment in canvas.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M2-Column-Aliasing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M2-Column-Aliasing/</guid><description>Column Aliasing Back: [[SQL Analytics M2 - Basic Querying]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M2-How-to-Complete-SQL-Assignments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M2-How-to-Complete-SQL-Assignments/</guid><description>How to Complete SQL Assignments Back: [[SQL Analytics M2 - Basic Querying]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M2-Installing-MySQL-Workbench-and-MariaDB/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M2-Installing-MySQL-Workbench-and-MariaDB/</guid><description>Installing MySQL Workbench and MariaDB Links MySQL :: Download MySQL Workbench *If you have an newer mac (M1 Chip) use macOS (ARM, 64-bit) Download MariaDB Server - MariaDB.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M2-Math-on-Columns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M2-Math-on-Columns/</guid><description>Math on Columns Back: [[SQL Analytics M2 - Basic Querying]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M2-MySQL-Workbench-Basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M2-MySQL-Workbench-Basics/</guid><description>MySQL Workbench Basics Back: [[SQL Analytics M2 - Basic Querying]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M2-ORDER-BY-LIMIT-and-Query-Structure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M2-ORDER-BY-LIMIT-and-Query-Structure/</guid><description>ORDERY BY, LIMIT, and Query Structure Back: [[SQL Analytics M2 - Basic Querying]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M2-SELECT-Statements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M2-SELECT-Statements/</guid><description>SELECT Statements Back: [[SQL Analytics M2 - Basic Querying]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M2-WHERE-Clause/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M2-WHERE-Clause/</guid><description>WHERE Clause Back: [[SQL Analytics M2 - Basic Querying]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M3-Aggregate-Functions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M3-Aggregate-Functions/</guid><description>Aggregate Functions Links CustomerScript -&amp;gt; Course-Resources/content/SQL-Files/CustomerScript.sql at hugo · kellerflint/Course-Resources (github.com) Back: [[SQL Analytics M3 - Grouping and Aggregation]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M3-GROUP-BY/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M3-GROUP-BY/</guid><description>GROUP BY Back: [[SQL Analytics M3 - Grouping and Aggregation]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M3-Grouping-and-Aggregation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M3-Grouping-and-Aggregation/</guid><description>Lessons and Practice - Grouping and Aggregation Use the Northwind database for all questions.
[[SQL Analytics M3 - NULL Values|Null Values]] (4 min) [[SQL Analytics M3 - Aggregate Functions|Aggregate Functions]] (10 min) Write a single query to display the minimum, average and maximum price of products and the total number of products.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M3-HAVING/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M3-HAVING/</guid><description>HAVING Back: [[SQL Analytics M3 - Grouping and Aggregation]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M3-NULL-Values/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M3-NULL-Values/</guid><description>NULL Values Links CustomerScript -&amp;gt; Course-Resources/content/SQL-Files/CustomerScript.sql at hugo · kellerflint/Course-Resources (github.com) Back: [[SQL Analytics M3 - Grouping and Aggregation]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M3-Understanding-Query-Order/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M3-Understanding-Query-Order/</guid><description>Understanding Query Order Back: [[SQL Analytics M3 - Grouping and Aggregation]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M4-SQL-for-Data-Analytics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M4-SQL-for-Data-Analytics/</guid><description>M4 SQL for Data Analytics Lessons and Example Scenario Example Dataset (if interested): https://github.com/kellerflint/Course-Resources/blob/hugo/content/SQL-Files/NetflixShowsScript.sql
M4 Peer Review Assignment - Video Game Market Analysis Assignment Background You are a data analyst working for a video game studio.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M5-Table-JOINs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M5-Table-JOINs/</guid><description>Table JOINs Use the Northwind Database for all questions.
Table Relationships Table JOINs Write a query to return the dates of all orders along with the countries and cities of customers who placed the order.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M6-Data-Types-and-Nullability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M6-Data-Types-and-Nullability/</guid><description>Data Types and Nullability In addition to showing basic structure of tables and their relationships, Entity Relationship Diagrams (ERDs) can also give us more insight into the columns.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M6-Entity-Relationship-Diagram-Structure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M6-Entity-Relationship-Diagram-Structure/</guid><description>Entity Relationship Diagram Structure Entity Relationship Diagrams come in various formats, but they share common elements that help us understand the architecture of a database.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M6-Entity-Relationship-Diagrams-and-Table-Creation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M6-Entity-Relationship-Diagrams-and-Table-Creation/</guid><description>Entity Relationship Diagrams and Creating Tables Understanding Entity Relationship Diagrams Entity Relationship Diagrams (ERDs) are a fundamental part of database design and architecture.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M6-Querying-from-Entity-Relationship-Diagrams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M6-Querying-from-Entity-Relationship-Diagrams/</guid><description>Querying from Entity Relationship Diagrams Practice questions College Courses Diagram Write a SQL query to retrieve the start date of all classes taught by the instructor with the first_name &amp;ldquo;Tina&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M6-Representing-Relationships/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M6-Representing-Relationships/</guid><description>Representing Relationships Entity Relationship Diagrams (ERDs) not only show us the entities and their attributes but also how these entities interact with each other.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M7-Composite-Primary-Keys/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M7-Composite-Primary-Keys/</guid><description>Back: [[SQL Analytics M7 - Many-to-Many Relationships and Entity Relationship Diagrams]] Composite Primary Keys Using Composite Primary Keys How do you know when to use a composite primary key vs create a new unique identifier?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M7-Many-to-Many-Relationships-and-Entity-Relationship-Diagrams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M7-Many-to-Many-Relationships-and-Entity-Relationship-Diagrams/</guid><description>Many-to-Many Relationships and Entity Relationship Diagrams [[SQL Analytics M7 - Many-to-Many Relationships|Many-to-Many Relationships]] (~10 min) [[SQL Analytics M7 - Table Aliasing|Table Aliasing]] (~3 min) Creating Entity Relationship Diagrams One-to-Many ER Diagrams Many-to-Many ER Diagrams [[SQL Analytics M7 - Composite Primary Keys]] (~6 min) Creating Entity Relationship Diagrams Link to the diagraming tool -&amp;gt; drawSQL ( https://drawsql.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M7-Many-to-Many-Relationships/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M7-Many-to-Many-Relationships/</guid><description>Back: [[SQL Analytics M7 - Many-to-Many Relationships and Entity Relationship Diagrams]] Many-to-Many Relationships Introduction to Many-to-Many Relationships A many-to-many relationship in databases occurs when multiple records in one table are associated with multiple records in another table.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M7-Table-Aliasing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M7-Table-Aliasing/</guid><description>Back: [[SQL Analytics M7 - Many-to-Many Relationships and Entity Relationship Diagrams]] Table Aliasing What is Table Aliasing? Table aliasing involves giving a table in your SQL query a temporary name.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M8-Database-Design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M8-Database-Design/</guid><description>M8 Database Design Intro Database Design Example Note: I&amp;rsquo;m using a different diagraming tool in this video but for your assignment use drawSQL ( https://drawsql.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M9-Database-Design-Peer-Review-Assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kellerflint.github.io/Course-Resources/SQL-Analytics-M9-Database-Design-Peer-Review-Assignment/</guid><description>M9 Peer Review Assignment - Database Design For this assignment, you will be designing and implementing a database to solve a business problem.</description></item></channel></rss>